# **ROBERT THOMAS**

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Personal Profile: An energetic, hardworking and enthusiastic individual experienced in drylining, ceiling fixing and a range of manufacturing operations. I have excellent practical skills and experience of using a range of equipment and machinery. Competent in all matters relating to health and safety as this is an important aspect of any job role. Able to use initiative to carry out work activities to the highest standard with the proven ability to work effectively as part of a team. A quick learner who is willing to undertake any necessary training and keen to further develop skills and knowledge in a challenging work environment.

### **WORK HISTORY**

### Rope access technician, 03/2024 to Current

#### Adss - Nationwide

- · Observed safety procedures while working at heights.
- Assembled temporary metal and wooden scaffolding on building sites.
- Removed debris from structural demolition to make way for new building projects.
- Completed building work at heights using scaffolding, reach equipment and strapping to climb structures.
- Cable pulling cable tray fitting

# Suspended ceiling fixer, 01/2016 to Current Self employed

- Suspended ceiling fixer, my job is to liaise with clients on solutions regard ceiling works, install ceilings and walls to British gypsum specifications as detailed on the drawing, different wall types ceiling type like sound acoustic fireproofing ect
- Residential and commercial properties of all size experienced under pressure and constantly working to tight deadlines to get projects finished on time in a clean and professional manner, running groups of people giving out instructions on how the job needs doing to what time line ect sorting out deliveries and liasing with Site management ect.
- Liaised with clients to effectively determine scope of work and bespoke specifications, performing quoting and cost estimating processes within [Timeframe].
- Adhered to health and safety procedures on construction sites.
- Dealt confidently with client queries in person when working in occupied domestic properties.

#### CONTACT

Address: 53 felstead road, Grimsby,

Lincolnshire DN344ET **Phone:** 07306811857

**Email:** 

Robertwthomas1992@gmail.com

**Date of Birth:** 30/04/1992 **Web:** Winda I.D RT052266GB

**LinkedIn:** http://linkedin.com/in/rober

t-thomas-b2208b147

#### SKILLS

- Maintaining hygiene and health & safety procedures
- · Working as part of a team
- Safe operation of equipment and machinery
- Using initiative to carry out work activities within a specific timescale
- · Motivated and enthusiastic
- Following instructions and procedures
- · Blueprint reading and interpretation
- Drylining
- Material cutting and shaping
- · Full UK driving license
- · Pipe covering techniques
- Plastering
- Construction drawing interpretation
- [Tool] usage
- · Cutting tools
- · Form grinding

### Warehouse assistant/delivery driver, 01/2014 to 01/2016 Howarth timber and Building Supplies

- My day to day duties include, loading and unloading HGV's using the forklift and sideloader, serving customers including tradesmen and the public cutting plywood, timber and other timber based products down to size
- My other duties include order picking, general cleaning duties and delivering stock to a local customer base round Lincolnshire.
- · Processed orders using handheld scanners with speed and precision.
- Cleaned and maintained warehouse equipment to guarantee proper working order.
- Ensured accuracy of outbound deliveries, verifying stock against dispatch documentation.
- Processed inbound stock deliveries, safely operating forklift equipment to unload and transport heavy pallets.
- Achieved daily auditing targets, working with pace and precision to effectively check stock accuracy.
- Facilitated smooth warehouse operations, employing excellent organisation and planning skills to optimise workspace use.

## General Labourer, 01/2010 to 01/2014 AB Ceilings - Grimsby

- My duties included assisting tradesmen, passing tools and materials, fetching and carrying, general labouring
- I maintained a clean tidy work environment and followed all health and safety procedures, working in various areas of the UK.
- · Operated forklift trucks and excavators.
- Performed strenuous physical activities such as heavy lifting in adverse conditions.
- · Stored, maintained and cleaned construction equipment.
- · Utilised PPE on site to prevent accidents.
- Operated concrete mixers, circular saws and cordless drills.

#### **EDUCATION**

IRATA ROPE ACCESS LEVEL 1, 03/2024
MCL LTD

First aid , Offshore , 02/2024 **Gwo** 

Fire safety , Offshore , 02/2024 Gwo

Sea survival , Offshore , 02/2024 **Gwo** 

Manual handling, Offshore, 02/2024

#### Gwo

Working at heights , Offshore , 02/2023 **Gwo** 

Confined space medium risk, 02/2024

**Gwo** - Grimsby , Lincolnshire

NVQ Level 2 FABRICATION AMD WELDING, ENGINEERING

Grimsby institute of further and higher education - Grimsby

BTEC TECHNICAL CERTIFICATE L2, Engineering

Grimsby institute of further and higher education - Grimsby

Cscs blue skilled worker card , Construction, 02/2024 Cscs - Grimsby

**NVQ Level 2 interior systems construction , Ceiling fixing Pro qual -** Grimsby , Lincolnshire

powered access license, Lift access equipment, 05/2021

IPaf - Grimsby, Lincolnshire

**Key skills level 2 , Numeracy Grimsby institute of further and higher education -** Grimsby , Lincolnshire

Key skills L2, Literacy

Grimsby institute of further and higher education - Grimsby

timber and mercenary Certification for **Panel saw, Grimsby Institute** - Wall saw Bandsaw Crosscut